so now that we have seen an example of
exception handling with our Obi let's do
an exceptions with our Obi quiz so let's
say that we have these instructions in
program order so this is the order in
which they are supposed to execute
according to the programmer let's say
that this is the current status of this
instruction the add is committed meaning
it has exited the pipeline and its
results have been committed from the
aerobee to the register file and so on
the load is executing meaning it has
left the reservation station it is now
doing its thing and the result still
hasn't been broadcast on the bus and the
load has not committed yet this ad is
done which means that it got a
reservation station it exited the
reservation station computed its result
deposited the result somewhere but the
result is still not committed meaning
the ad still hasn't left the processor
the divide is also executing like the
load here meaning it has read these
registers and now it's slowly computing
its result this ad is done meaning it
has computed its result but it still
hasn't committed and this ad is also
done let's say that this divided when
the status of these instructions is like
this has an exception so while it's
executing we discover for example that
it's been trying to divide by 0 so this
ad now has an exception the question for
you is what is the new status of these
instructions after this exception has
been handled meaning what is the new
status at the point at which we can go
to the exception handler